<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Ekholm</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eric Ekholm</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Eric Ekholm</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:53:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:53:20 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is a selected list of projects I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on or have worked on recently:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;brain&#34;&gt;Brain&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ekholme.github.io/brain&#34;&gt;Brain&lt;/a&gt; is my &amp;ldquo;second brain.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a collection of notes on things that interest me, including stats, coding, baking, and fitness, among others. Feel free to poke around!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;edudata&#34;&gt;Edudata&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://edudata.blog&#34;&gt;Edudata&lt;/a&gt; is a blog I write about topics loosely connected to education and data. I used to publish posts weekly, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing less regularly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:34:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-ai-policy&#34;&gt;My AI Policy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t use AI to write anything you read here, or on any of my other sites. I enjoy writing, plus it helps me think, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to farm my writing or thinking out to our AI overlords.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That said, I do use AI for some things, including fact-checking understanding of certain topics (this is mostly relevant for my notes site) or for helping with technical non-writing things around the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:02:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Eric! I&amp;rsquo;m a data scientist and education researcher. I am currently a data scientist for Chesterfield County Public Schools, where I use data to help guide decisions and improve both students&amp;rsquo; and teachers&amp;rsquo; educational experiences. In my free time, I enjoy reading, writing, coding, working out, baking, and spending time with friends &amp;amp; family (including my pup, Nala).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I earned my PhD in educational psychology from VCU in 2019. In my &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholarscompass.vcu.edu/etd/5977/&#34;&gt;dissertation&lt;/a&gt;, I studied how writers&amp;rsquo; emotional states influenced their productivity as well as the day-to-day inertia of these emotional states.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning my Website to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/transition-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:35:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/transition-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past several years, I&amp;rsquo;ve built my personal website using &lt;a href=&#34;https://quarto.org/&#34;&gt;Quarto&lt;/a&gt;. Before that, I was using Rmarkdown. So the transition to Quarto wasn&amp;rsquo;t really even a switch in philosophy; rather, it was more like upgrading to a different piece of software that did basically the same thing&amp;hellip;only better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, though, I decided I wanted to simplify my website, and part of this simplification entails switching from Quarto to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; to build my site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
